[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339570", "question": "Who gets a visit from Santa Claus in, The Christmas That Almost Wasn't?", "answer": "Attorney Sam Whipple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b370ea1c3f17ccc40c8e1a", "question": "A pub that is required to sell beer primarily from a single brewery is typically referred to as what?", "answer": "Tied house", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b2a101dd7bf43be5e7a0", "question": "What is the ultimate goal of the Chinese design practice, feng shui?", "answer": "Harness energy and establish harmony", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47d", "question": "What is the Gulf Stream?", "answer": "Warm ocean current in the Atlantic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600787ce0eee65b76b9f265d", "question": "According to Greek mythology who was the first woman on earth?", "answer": "Pandora", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac56", "question": "What landlocked European country remained neutral in both World Ware I and World War II?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93c", "question": "The phrase \"banana republic\" was first coined by O. Henry in reference to what country?", "answer": "Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cf", "question": "What country was policed by the Blackshirts for almost 25 years?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdab94a0b8cce1e6fda7054", "question": "Which person is known for publishing \"The Interpretation of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Sigmund Freud", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600395cf57a0e35c43f83896", "question": "What is the term for a three-dimensional composition made from a variety of traditionally non-artistic materials and objects?", "answer": "Assemblage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b62a", "question": "What are known as \"buddy stores\"?", "answer": "Aircraft fuel tanks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cc", "question": "What day did the Battle of the Somme end?", "answer": "November 18, 1916", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d076cb870e6f05ba60085e", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", who is the shrew's more desireable sister?", "answer": "Bianca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febab537e83c707845b20e7", "question": "Which planet is referred to as the \"jewel of the solar system\"?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3eae238e4e5d4832e6316", "question": "The AMRAAM missile was designed to replace what other missile?", "answer": "Sparrow missile", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394aa", "question": "Who claims to have invented the name \"Remington Steele\"?", "answer": "Laura Holt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ddfffe83fe1f2a824b68", "question": "What conflict was instigated by Aristagoras of Miletus?", "answer": "Persian War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c461", "question": "\"Ships of the desert\" are what?", "answer": "Camels", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339066", "question": "What does the Latin word \"Verbatim\" literally means?", "answer": "Word for word", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6a", "question": "Who was the head football coach of the Miami Hurricanes from 1995 to \u00ad2000?", "answer": "Butch Davis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c3", "question": "In what year did Martin Luther King Jr. deliver his \"I Have a  Dream\" speech?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7cf", "question": "In 1986, a brittle O-ring seal was determined to be the cause of what?", "answer": "The Challenger disaster", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bd3d877e98cb97778957", "question": "What is the flattest continent?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03a", "question": "Where is the Popliteal Fossa located?", "answer": "Back of the knee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfbed0003d27d341092bd1", "question": "What is Antarctica\u2019s tallest volcano?", "answer": "Mount Sidley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b278", "question": "During one of his famous freedom-of-speech cases, who wore an American flag to court as a diaper?", "answer": "Larry Flynt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af34", "question": "Which treaty ended the war between Germany and the Allied Powers in World War I?", "answer": "Treaty of Versailles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cca0877e98cb97778a28", "question": "What country would you have to visit to enjoy a taste of Hymettus honey?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903a", "question": "Under what pen name did Hector Hugh Munro write?", "answer": "Saki", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdcfaec223966ae8f88fb", "question": "In the film \"Goodfellas\", what airline is robbed?", "answer": "Lufthansa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9c", "question": "What Kellogg's product was introduced to compete with Post's unsuccessful \"Country Squares\"?", "answer": "Pop-Tarts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b57183c67df192a942e335c", "question": "Which stretch of water seperates Tierra del Fuego from the rest of South America?", "answer": "Strait of Magellan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fa", "question": "What metal do you get from Hematite?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b631", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"A\" referred to as?", "answer": "Alpha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ed", "question": "Into which bay does the Golden Gate Strait lead?", "answer": "San Francisco Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398bd", "question": "Who was the final act at Woodstock?", "answer": "Jimi Hendrix", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c89e08011619dd6d41548a", "question": "What is the name of the reality series Token made featuring mobility scooter-bound Cartman in the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Here Comes Fatty Doo Doo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc1183469bb8041d07a075", "question": "In cooking, what is cutting herbs or vegetables into very fine strips called?", "answer": "Chiffonade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec3", "question": "Who created the New Model Army?", "answer": "Oliver Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbe446ce05a3942286eeb", "question": "In the film \"Red Dragon,\" Hannibal Lector speculates Will Graham is wearing what brand of shaving lotion?", "answer": "Old Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fe", "question": "What compound makes up around 60% of the human body weight?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008b7acf842fa4c4ba9699", "question": "What is a funambulist?", "answer": "Tightrope walker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdd3eec223966ae8f8902", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65e2b1f3c0ead6880d627", "question": "Who developed world's first color e-book reader?", "answer": "Fujitsu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc5", "question": "Monza and Silverstone are venues for which sport?\u00a0", "answer": "Formula One Racing\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96ee623c87fd04dd15e3e", "question": "What general betrayed the U.S. after being passed up for a promotion?", "answer": "Benedict Arnold", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47b", "question": "Which stretch of water is Europe's most northern boundary?", "answer": "Arctic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de4", "question": "In the TV show \"Twin Peaks\", what letter was found under Laura Palmer's fingernail?", "answer": "R", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d1", "question": "How did Norman E. Shumway make medical history?", "answer": "He performed the first successful transplant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a899dd160d398dc9cf7a6af", "question": "Who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?", "answer": "Henry Kissinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e61", "question": "What word for a wimp comes from the title character of Harold Webster's comic strip \"The Timid Soul\"?", "answer": "Milquetoast", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f4684af848b908361b876", "question": "As of 2020, what is the highest grossing film of all time without taking inflation into account?", "answer": "Avengers: Endgame", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb582f5dad637d903c880f", "question": "What animal is considered to be symbolic of Venice?", "answer": "Lion -- The Lion of St. Mark is a symbol that appears throughout the city.  It honors St. Mark, who is the patron saint of Venice.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8ac9701dd7bf43be5e76e", "question": "Which religion places importance on proper care for bonsai trees?", "answer": "Zen Buddhism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b2", "question": "What is the heaviest breed of bear?", "answer": "Polar bear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905d", "question": "What year did poet Sylvia Plath die?", "answer": "1963", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca44", "question": "What is the chemical name for lye?", "answer": "Sodium Hydroxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f6e7fe83fe1f2a824c1e", "question": "After his crucifixion, who takes down the body of Jesus Christ off the cross of Calvary?", "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a916", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort McHenry?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31f", "question": "What is the most common element in air?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6f", "question": "Who wrote the novel series \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6587aae7e414034b5aef1", "question": "What year did Ronald Reagan send American troops to Grenada?", "answer": "1983", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad5", "question": "How many zeroes are in the number one trillion?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a91", "question": "Where did the Yellow Brick Road lead to?", "answer": "Emerald City", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb63", "question": "In what European country is the headquarters for the World Health Organization?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3c7944f0f6af5b066631", "question": "Ranidaphobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Frogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e18cfe83fe1f2a824b96", "question": "Where was the French surrender to Germany signed?", "answer": "In a railway car", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e97b06d333868d34d756", "question": "During World War II, what was the purpose of \"Operation Detachment\"?", "answer": "Capture Iwo Jima", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339717", "question": "Which 1995 movie stars Susan Sarandon and Sean Penn?", "answer": "Dead Man Walking", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca5", "question": "Who wrote the science-fiction novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac15", "question": "The Union of the Comoros is located on the northern end of which water channel?", "answer": "Mozambique Channel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339377", "question": "How many Oscars did the 1997 movie \"Titanic\" win?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a1e1cc7b5a031299b745735", "question": "Which brothers published the storybook entitled \"Children's and Household Tales\" in the 19th century?", "answer": "The brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ac", "question": "Julia Roberts and Hugh Grant were paired in what romantic comedy?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c548", "question": "How wide is the average bolt of lightning?", "answer": "1/2 inch", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d116614fea7fe947a2226f", "question": "Who played the role of Seth Brundle in the 1986 film \"The Fly\"?", "answer": "Jeff Goldblum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d13", "question": "What is Linus and Lucy's last name in \"Peanuts\" comics?", "answer": "Van Pelt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd03", "question": "It is sometimes considered a fashion faux pas to wear white after what holiday?", "answer": "Labor Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601370e11381754895396386", "question": "What baseball player had the nickname \"Sultan of Swat\"?", "answer": "George Herman \"Babe\" Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e8", "question": "Which European state has an area of 0.44 square kilometers?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e10", "question": "Philosopher Hannah Arendt's most famous book is named for what man \"in Jerusalem\"?", "answer": "Adolf Eichmann", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c366", "question": "What shape is the piston in a \"Wankel\" engine?", "answer": "Triangular", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5df", "question": "What was ornithologist Robert Stroud's nickname?", "answer": "The Birdman of Alcatraz", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59636c06967692ea851899a7", "question": "How many years after the 1990\u2019s movie \"Independence Day\", was sequel \"Independence Day: Resurgence\" released?", "answer": "20 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f98", "question": "In the traditional song, what did the children dance around \"on a cold and frosty morning\"?", "answer": "The mulberry bush", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b372861c3f17ccc40c8e25", "question": "The Moho is an extinct genus of birds that were endemic to which island archipelago?", "answer": "Hawaiian Islands", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a1e1dd9b5a031299b74573e", "question": "What century did the Icelandic Vikings first reach the island of Newfoundland?", "answer": "11th Century", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ba", "question": "What was the name of the first album released by the 1990's German band \"Snap!\"?", "answer": "World Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338caa", "question": "According to the novel, about how long was Robinson Crusoe marooned on his remote island?", "answer": "28 years", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015eaf2fe83fe1f2a824bf6", "question": "Which Native American tribe took part in the first Thanksgiving feast?", "answer": "Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ab", "question": "In which city is the Taj Mahal?", "answer": "Agra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec6", "question": "What is the person who makes charcoal called?", "answer": "Collier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f3052145aa2bc17b61b2ac8", "question": "Chisinau is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Moldova", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912a", "question": "What year was Camille Saint-Saens' opera \"Samson and Delilah\" first performed?", "answer": "1877", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea77dfff048f679a45abd0", "question": "What breed of domestic cat is known for swimming?", "answer": "Turkish Van", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb8b07e83c707845b2135", "question": "Abraham Lincoln, Julius Caesar, Tutankhamen and Osama bin Laden all suffered from what disorder?", "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff146e2b0ee8c595b6d39c1", "question": "What is the oldest operating Broadway theater?", "answer": "The Lyceum Theater", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72b", "question": "What organ in the human body produces insulin?", "answer": "Pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cfb7877e98cb97778a52", "question": "Knoxville, Tennessee sits on the bank of what river?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887d", "question": "Who was King Lear's favorite daughter?", "answer": "Cordelia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4d968908b8581f80b092a7", "question": "How old did Canada turn on July 1, 2017?", "answer": "150 years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c941", "question": "What is a group of larks called?", "answer": "Exaltation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c163", "question": "What airport has the code MME?", "answer": "Durham Tees Valley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad0d", "question": "Which popular Greek philosopher is said to have tutored Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Aristotle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe699fd20565ad31a57c74f", "question": "What 19th-century engineer devised an internal combustion engine which works without a spark plug?", "answer": "Rudolf Diesel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636c4c967692ea851899a9", "question": "What beer brand shares a name with one of the Founding Father of the United States?", "answer": "Samuel Adams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c88e83422f44c2d77a29c46", "question": "Reaching 20,320 feet (6,194 meters) above sea level, Denali is located in what US state?", "answer": " Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b239", "question": "What royal subject married Grace Kelly?", "answer": "Rainier III of Monaco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf5", "question": "Which country borders Kyrgystan to the east?", "answer": "China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937eb8808d98002fdd633af", "question": "In which city would you find Red Square?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d3", "question": "In The Simpsons, how are the out-of-control robots at Itchy & Scratchy Land stopped?", "answer": "Flash photography", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c9b49076251badbead8", "question": "Who was the first American to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He orbited the Earth three times in five hours in a Mercury space capsule he named \"Friendship 7\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Bart Gets an 'F',\" what sickness does Lisa have?", "answer": "Mumps", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e99e2ebfabb9c85d8a976", "question": "Berlin stands on the banks of which river?", "answer": "Spree", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a0", "question": "Which of the Hawaiian Islands is nicknamed the \"Garden Isle\"?", "answer": "Kauai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25af1b63e5727cf5a4857", "question": "The song \"(Everything I Do) I Do It for You\" was the title track to which film?", "answer": "Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e1f1fe83fe1f2a824b9a", "question": "After changing sides during World War II, what was Italy's primary objective?", "answer": "It distracted Germany from accomplishing its main objectives", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a0", "question": "What\u2019s the name of the science of growing plants in liquid nutrients instead of soil?", "answer": "Hydroponics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008dbabf4f3bc4a292f8619", "question": "Which country was the first to recognize the Republic of Texas?", "answer": "France (In 1841, France opened a legation in Austin and the Republic of Texas opened an embassy in Paris.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b373281c3f17ccc40c8e2b", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b863", "question": "What is the highest possible bowling score in a game with no strikes?", "answer": "190", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e9a606d333868d34d757", "question": "During World War II, the U.S. purchase more than 150 million pounds of what to feed its troops?", "answer": "SPAM", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b998", "question": "In the standard Monopoly game, what place will you land on if you roll 9 when on Park Avenue?", "answer": "Oriental Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb1", "question": "From 1997-2002, what computer company used the ad slogan \"Think different\"?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96e9e23c87fd04dd15e3a", "question": "As of 2020, who was the last human to walk on the moon?", "answer": "Eugene Cernan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323117bf195a31e15d7381", "question": "Bugs Bunny was a satirical interpretation of what actor?", "answer": "Clark Gable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600242ee4be4723ccac2218f", "question": "In Jane Austen\u2019s \"Pride and Prejudice\", what is the name of the pompous clergyman who marries Elizabeth\u2019s sister, Charlotte?", "answer": "Mr. Collins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9df", "question": "Which branch of science is concerned with the study of matter and energy?", "answer": "Physics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3e", "question": "What 1998 war film was loosely based on the real-life case of the Niland brothers?", "answer": "Saving Private Ryan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd5", "question": "What movie's title character is given a new name when he's seen playing with Two Socks?", "answer": "Dances with Wolves'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a7796c0f9723ab15cb5f", "question": "How many US dollars are a pound of dimes and a pound of quarters each worth?", "answer": "$20 each", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bc", "question": "\"Jumpman\" originally was the name of which Nintendo mascot?", "answer": "Mario", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a44", "question": "What author created the characters Ponyboy and Sodapop?", "answer": "S.E. Hinton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9b", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Raytown?", "answer": "Mama's Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b589", "question": "What does a Turk call \"Turkish Delight\"?", "answer": "Lokum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f8abfa5fdd6dd25324f0", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d08", "question": "What mythological figure flew too close to the sun, and fell into the sea and drown when the sun melted the wax on his wings?", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe0e28efcbed638185eaa1e", "question": "\"Chili crab\" is a dish from which country?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb650f5dad637d903c8833", "question": "What African ethnic group is known as \"the people of the veil\" because the men wear veils that conceal all but their eyes?", "answer": "Tuareg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab81", "question": "What country borders Guinea to the south?", "answer": "Sierra Leone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121d2863c99d48cd169b1b", "question": "The \"Maman\" sculpture in Bilbao, Spain is a giant what?", "answer": "Spider - The huge arachnid is modeled after the artist Louise Bourgeois\u2019s mother. It was her representation of her weaver mother.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fac", "question": "What TV title character lived at 485 Mapleton Drive, Mayfield?", "answer": "Beaver Cleaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a7596c0f9723ab15cb5e", "question": "Which US college or university has the largest endowment?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c411", "question": "What element has the atomic number 26?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f1676af7c52aae91cc07b9", "question": "The Republic of Guinea-Bissau is located on which African coast?", "answer": "Western coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4f", "question": "Which US president died three months after being shot by Charles J. Guiteau?", "answer": "James Garfield", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26d", "question": "What is a nanominute?", "answer": "One-billionth of a minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c34e9815febcc896f9257", "question": "What continent is Sao Tome and Principe located in?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f521ff048f679a45aad2", "question": "Nosocomephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Hospitals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03c", "question": "What was the name of the sect that was raided by the FBI in Waco, Texas in 1993?", "answer": "Branch Davidians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a162ac7f01ec323f8491725", "question": "In 1967 what new safety measure and device were introduced to the UK?", "answer": "Blood alcohol level and the breathalyzer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a134", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl's father?", "answer": "Cole Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64e", "question": "What media personality was once a speechwriter for Richard Nixon?", "answer": "Ben Stein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008a5dcf842fa4c4ba9690", "question": "What nationality was Johnny Weissmuller?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6d", "question": "Who played the role of TV's E. L. Turner?", "answer": "Ben Vereen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a83c", "question": "How many US states border Ohio?", "answer": "5", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cb", "question": "Which Kellogg's cereal was advertised by Tusk Tusk the Elephant?", "answer": "Choco Krispis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b696", "question": "What appears with the king of diamonds on a standard English deck of cards?", "answer": "An axe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb1", "question": "Who was the father of Cleopatra's twins?", "answer": "Mark Antony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d076e3870e6f05ba60085f", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", what is the shrew's last name?", "answer": "Minola", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37b", "question": "Who conquered the Matterhorn in 1865?", "answer": "Edward Whymper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf8", "question": "In what year was the Twinkie invented?", "answer": "1930", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5be580225415ba52ed6f0ab1", "question": "The TV show \"Soap\", was set in what fictional town?", "answer": "Dunn's River, Connecticut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ed2606d333868d34d76a", "question": "What game came bundled with the first Nintendo Game Boy in America?", "answer": "Tetris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3f1e44f0f6af5b066650", "question": "Morello is a variety of which fruit?", "answer": "Cherry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c76", "question": "What philosopher/author lived on the shores of Walden Pond?", "answer": "Henry David Thoreau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0b", "question": "Hockey legend Wayne Gretzky was born in what year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff668a652a821ff76ae8b07", "question": "How many electors make up the Electoral College in the U.S.?", "answer": "538", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b22", "question": "What is the name of the little people in \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Munchkins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c223", "question": "Petroselinum crispum is the Latin name of which herb?", "answer": "Parsley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c450", "question": "What fiber-producing plant is attacked by the boll weevil?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3fbec73aa70ea0b70b03", "question": "For the film \"The Empire Strikes Back,\" where were scenes set on the ice planet Hoth actually filmed?", "answer": "The Battle of Hoth scenes were shot on Handangerjokulen Glacier near the village of Finse, Norway.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f749ea9e54d890926f6fb", "question": "Georgia, it\u2019s illegal to eat what with a fork?", "answer": "Fried chicken", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b59", "question": "In Greek mythology, how many labours were imposed on Hercules?", "answer": "12", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a787", "question": "What important crop is the Rhine Valley in Germany known for growing?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31d", "question": "What is added to bread to make it swell?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fc", "question": "In which 1966 science fiction film did Stephen Boyd star alongside Raquel Welch?", "answer": "Fantastic Voyage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ee", "question": "What European country is named for the dark-looking Dinaric Alps?", "answer": "Montenegro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5901d794709c1c34536e6ea3", "question": "What was the first flavor of the malt beverage named \"Zima\"?", "answer": "Lemon-Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa5b473838c5c8a417f2a", "question": "Automatonophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Ventriloquist dummies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa47", "question": "What is the principal river of Ireland?", "answer": "River Shannon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff25a4331a458464a93c46f", "question": "What is the process called by which people set out to amass large amounts of in-game currency to sell in the real world?", "answer": "Gold farming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949a", "question": "Who played European John Blackthorne in the miniseries \"Shogun\"?", "answer": "Richard Chamberlain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c7", "question": "What nickname was given to the brutal Royal Irish Constabulary Reserve Force in 1920?", "answer": "Black and Tans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133accd", "question": "Who was known as \"Moses\" of the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3389ff048f679a45aaef", "question": "What animal name literally means \"pig-fish\"?", "answer": "Porpoise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9fc", "question": "In what city are the famous Tivoli Gardens?", "answer": "Copenhagen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7d", "question": "Freetown is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Sierra Leone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06f", "question": "Tin or aluminum is the traditional gift for which anniversary?", "answer": "Tenth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa3420565ad31a57c812", "question": "Who was President Gerald Ford's vice president?", "answer": "Nelson Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1b", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Gudmundsdottir?", "answer": "Bj\u00f6rk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca56", "question": "What do insects do through their spiracles?", "answer": "Breathe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e970a7ccba3ffe45786f6", "question": "What is the fear of bees known as?", "answer": "Melissophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa86a6ce05a3942286ed0", "question": "Who was originally to be cast as Axel Foley in the film \"Beverly Hills Cop\"?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b0", "question": "What Canadian singer was married to Mutt Lange?", "answer": "Shania Twain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e0", "question": "What year saw the release of the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8fb", "question": "The Bitterroot Range of the Rockies is located on the border between what two US states?", "answer": "Idaho and Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe2583f658e585fda9cfa3e", "question": "Black Forest cake originates from which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d118314fea7fe947a22282", "question": "Which part of the body is dermatology concerned with?", "answer": "The skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8e", "question": "What Australian city's pro basketball team was called the Devils?", "answer": "Hobart's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc2", "question": "Who is the Greek god of love?", "answer": "Eros", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea43a0ff048f679a45ab84", "question": "What kind of star system is Algol?", "answer": "A binary star system", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c078", "question": "Genuphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Knees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ef", "question": "What does P.S. stand for at the end of a letter?", "answer": "Postscript", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133896b", "question": "What is the better-known name of crime fiction writer Lady Mallowan D.B.E.?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f721aa9e54d890926f6ea", "question": "In which ocean can you find Australia\u2019s Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Pacific -- It is comprised of over 3,000 reef systems and contains over 400 different types of coral and is visible from space.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950b", "question": "Who plays the role of Martin Riggs in the Lethal Weapon movie series?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8c", "question": "Alfred Jingle appears in which Dickens novel?", "answer": "The Pickwick Papers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c1", "question": "What kind of animal is raised in a warren?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1a", "question": "What was the nickname of character Freddie Stubbs on the 1970's sitcom \"What's Happening!!\"?", "answer": "Rerun", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a4", "question": "What is the longest river in Europe?", "answer": "Volga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339531", "question": "What show debuted in 1963 and became the longest running sci-fi series?", "answer": "Doctor Who", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f06", "question": "What author created the character of Nero Wolfe?", "answer": "Rex Stout", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58d", "question": "By what name is the spinal disease \"amyotrophic lateral sclerosis\" better known?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig's disease", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49b", "question": "Which country were the 1912 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df5", "question": "What Broadway team collaborated on \"Flora the Red Menace\" before writing \"Cabaret\" and \"Chicago\"?", "answer": "John Kander and Fred Ebb", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7d", "question": "Which US president ordered the first troops into Vietnam, starting the ground war for the US?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc4", "question": "The majority of the World's real cinnamon comes from what island nation?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25eed16682715b82711cd1", "question": "Which European country strted colonizing Venezuela in 1522?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c349", "question": "In computer science, what does the acronym GIGO stand for?", "answer": "Garbage In, Garbage Out", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c379", "question": "What name is given to male rhinoceroses?", "answer": "Bulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a94e661d1b4d384d5d673", "question": "Elzie Segar created what popular character?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b63ee662d71a53651004", "question": "In Herman Melville\u2019s novel \"Moby Dick\", who was the loyal, reasonable first mate?", "answer": "Starbuck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f0", "question": "What is frozen to make dry ice?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d1156e4fea7fe947a22266", "question": "In the 1975 novel \"The Moneychangers\", what is the name of Alex Vandervoort's wife?", "answer": "Celia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ccf7bb0b37b32637bdc44c6", "question": "In what year was the language learning site/app Duolingo launched?", "answer": "2011", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c759", "question": "What human organs are affected by glaucoma?", "answer": "The eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a7", "question": "The original TV show \"Star Trek\" aired for how many seasons?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3c", "question": "How many on-field players are there in a standard Australian rules football team?", "answer": "Eighteen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab5", "question": "What is the technical term for earwax?", "answer": "Cerumen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a648", "question": "What does the 49th parallel separate Montana from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b490049076251badbeaaa", "question": "The Treaty of Ghent was the peace treaty that ended which war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc1fbec223966ae8f8871", "question": "What singer was born in Havana in 1957, the daughter of a bodyguard employed by dictator Fulgencio Batista?", "answer": "Gloria Estefan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf6", "question": "In which movie did Billie Burke portray a witch?", "answer": "The Wizard of Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cb02bb53d1af658864d5", "question": "What year did Hallmark made its first Christmas cards?", "answer": "1915", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea46ffff048f679a45aba7", "question": "What does \"PO\" stand for on a prescription?", "answer": "By mouth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da3", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Canadian Bacon\"?", "answer": "Alan Alda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb356992627b8fe95581bdf", "question": "What is the name of the tallest flagpole in the world?", "answer": "The Jeddah Flagpole", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb68cb5dad637d903c8844", "question": "The unofficial Wei\u00dfwurst\u00e4quator, or \"white sausage equator\", separates Bavaria and the south from the rest of which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19e", "question": "When was tennis player, Martina Hingis, born?", "answer": "1980", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70c57f96e155acab35d2b", "question": "Which planet in the Solar System has moons named after characters from Shakespeare's plays?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a1", "question": "Which band comprises sisters Andrea, Sharon, and Caroline with their brother Jim?", "answer": "The Corrs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe528911bf59ab7d2e380fe", "question": "Who coined the phrase \"15 minutes of fame\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf2", "question": "Who created the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "Tomohiro Nishikado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921d", "question": "In which movie does Hugh Grant play a London bookshop owner?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338926", "question": "Who is the father of the Hulkling?", "answer": "Captain Marvel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddbfe6ce05a3942286d96", "question": "Which classic Christmas film premiered in theaters during the summer?", "answer": "\"Miracle on 34th Street\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fbbfa4edfd43a087adbd", "question": "What does a Forensic Pathologist typically perform?", "answer": "Autopsies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba4", "question": "What country is located immediately north of Sudan?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b8f6364247bf200fb885", "question": "What is the capital of the Australia's Northern Territory?", "answer": "Darwin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a142", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Gasoline Alley\"?", "answer": "Rod Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd821ffd0de9af39e9d46a7", "question": "What was the first species of animal sent to space?", "answer": "Fruit Fly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1b", "question": "What author created the land of Pellucidar?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}]